Guide to the David X. Young Films, 1955-2007 RL.10002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual, 1955-2007; 1; 97 items
  - Other film reels, 1955-1985 and undated; 5; 29 items
    - Ordeal of Jonathan Cashew (1962); Margery's dance (circa 1968); Gamsey crazy Cape party footage (circa 1968); all original black and white; black-and-white, silent
      - 16mm original, 1962-1968; 37 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0029)
    - Original Lowell Cape ftg; Organon work print; Fishpix work print; color and black-and-white, silent
      - 16mm original, 1964-1968; 31 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0034)
    - Hotel del Phrelgo; Grafix (color); Aune's daughter dance; Rolling the quirt; No Smoke; Christine's ass (color); color and black-and-white, silent
      - 16mm original, 1965-1969; 42 minutes (Box 5, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0014)
    - Original Bleak House; Eliza crib; Esso; Fish ftg.; color, silent
      - 16mm original, 1966-1968; 28 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0033)
    - Original Fishkill; Fife; Auction; color and black-and-white, silent
      - 16mm original, 1966-1967; 25 minutes (Box 1, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0032)
    - ASJr wp orig track; color and black-and-white, silent and sound
      - 16mm original, circa 1967; 25 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0016)
    - Invitation Dinner's Club commercial; black-and-white, sound
      - 16mm original, circa 1967; 2 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16OS-0002)
    - Australian newsfilm; color, silent
      - 16mm original, circa 1967; 12 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0026)
    - 1967 Original Nasty Aunts; Fishkill; Aquarium; Tong; color, silent
      - 16mm original, 1967; 27 minutes (Box 1, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0024)
    - 1968 Cape Maine Ftg. on Robt Lowell - Original; 1968 Organon Original; Cold War; color, silent
      - 16mm original, 1968; 26 minutes (Box 1, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0023)
    - Cold war; color, silent
      - 16mm original, 1968; 39 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0035)
    - Eastham, Spring '70; color, silent
      - Super 8mm original, 1970; 3 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F8-0003)
    - untitled; color, silent and sound
      - 16mm original, circa 1980; 2 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0037)
    - Every child dreams of power in paradise titles; RWA Congo titles; A matter of history titles; Busted licks titles; Klaximo titles; color, silent
      - 16mm original, 1985; 5 minutes (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-0036)
    - "Blank"; full-coat magnetic soundtrack
      - 16mm original, undated; 23 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F16MAG-0013)
    - "Music"; full-coat magnetic soundtrack
      - 16mm original, undated; 14 minutes (Box 1, Film-reel RL10002-F16MAG-0014)
    - Promised land mono track; full-coat magnetic soundtrack
      - 16mm original, undated; 7 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F16MAG-0015)
    - A trip to the Cape; color, silent
      - 8mm original, undated; 15 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F8-0001)
    - Dave; color, silent
      - Super 8mm original, undated; 2 minutes (Box 7, Film-reel RL10002-F8-0002)
    - 16 inserts/cuts/outtakes not on reels or cores, measuring 3 inches to 5 feet
      - 16mm original, undated; no content (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-Cuts 01)
    - 10 inserts/cuts/outtakes not on reels or cores, measuring 3 inches to 5 feet
      - 16mm original, undated; no content (Box 2, Film-reel RL10002-F16-Cuts 02)
  - Other videocassettes, 1999 May 17-26; 6; 29 items
    The videocassettes in this series include four VHS tapes recorded from broadcasts featuring information on W. Eugene Smith, and one Hi-8 tape from 1999 that is possibly a home video of Cape Cod.
    This series is arranged chronologically.
    - W.E. Smith, t.v. shows about, 0-2770 Cablevision show, 2/83 K.P. Smith on W.E. Smith, interviewed by Derringer. 2775-3010 3/2/86 CBS Sunday Morning show
      - VHS videocassette original, 1983 February, 1986 March 2; no content (Box 9, Video-cassette RL10002-VHS-0009)
    - Smith 4, Eric, 30H, 2-12-96
      - VHS videocassette original, 1996 February 12; no content (Box 9, Video-cassette RL10002-VHS-0006)
    - Cape, May 17-May 26, 1999
      - VHS videocassette original, 1983-1999 and undated; no content (Box 8, Video-cassette RL10002-Hi8-0001)
    - W.E. Smith
      - VHS videocassette original, undated; no content (Box 9, Video-cassette RL10002-VHS-0007)
    - Jim Hughes on W.E. Smith
      - VHS videocassette original, undated; 5 items; no content (Box 9, Video-cassette RL10002-VHS-0008)
  - Other audiocassettes, undated; 7; 9 items
    The audiocassettes in this series include tapes made from radio broadcasts, as well as one tape from 1991 of David X. Young playing piano.
    - Religion, law and legitimate Government - Daniel Sheehan
      - Audiocassette original, 1991 and undated (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0009)
    - DX piano 11/91 1
      - Audiocassette original, 1991 November; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0004)
    - Bop and Bird mix
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0007)
    - Milt Jackson KCR 10
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0006)
    - Milt Jackson KCR 9, 1966 Japan concert MJQ
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0005)
    - June Christy and Stan Kenton; Bob and Ray, 1949
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0003)
    - "I Ching, DNA, and change," Ken Phillips
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0002)
    - Terrance McKenna - Art, psychedelics and creativity, Calif.
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0008)
    - Braff; mix
      - Audiocassette original, undated; no content (Box 8, Audio-cassette RL10002-CS-0001)